## Jens Krause

# Reliability and stability drive business

I'm a professionell software developer since 2002, I worked with all kinds of customers and projects from startup to highly corporate settings. Even though the requirements are vastly different there, some truth apply all the way through from small to big business: - nobody likes surprises when it comes to code deployments/updates - broken code are bad for your customers and may exposes severe security risks - patching the broken parts is more stressful and less effective the developing clean first place

After endless nightshifts fixing problems in sloppy coded legacy projects I'm a strong proposer of automated testing. Write the test-case before coding ensures that the requirements are already clear and avoids wasted hours in implementing and fixing flawed logic. It leads to testable, modular code which is mostly free of surprises and helps to identify issues before the went into production environments.

It is in the very interest of any software based company to have a solid code foundation, which leads to overall faster developing times, better portability and most importantly stability. After all, stability pays the bills.

#### **Technical Skills**

Likes: python php scrum performance testing jekyll continuous-integration api security

Dislikes: hardware database-design java

## Experience

#### Senior Developer - RapidAgileSoftware

Jul 2019 → Current

python, php, javascript, jekyll, cookiecutter, unit-testing, automated-tests, html, css, wordpress, api

Working on contractual basis on customer projects with a strong passion for open-source, rapid and agile development while delivering high quality and reliability.

### $\textbf{Senior Developer} - \underline{crazy\text{-}factory.com}$

Jan 2016 → Jun 2019

 $php,\ payment-gateway,\ stripe-payments,\ security,\ continuous-integration,\ automated-tests,\ unit-testing,\ build-automation$ 

Senior Developer at crazy-factory.com, responsible for payment workflow implementations, continuous integration, testing and education of Junior Developers

**Director of Webservices** – Propertyshelf Inc., propertyshelf.com plone, diazo, python, scrum, seo, project-management

Apr 2011  $\rightarrow$  Nov 2015

My job requires to coordinate international projects with customers, designers and developers from all over the world. The focus is on real estate clients in Central America as Costa Rica, Ecuador and Nicaragua, but we also serve customers in the USA, Europe and Asia. We try to get our customers properties indexed in the very first ranks of the search engine results, while implementing full responsive themes, fitting today's requirements to push their business-success.

## **Technical Choices**

- · don't panic, use python!
- Plone CMS SEO, security & stability are awesome out-of-the-box
- Diazo-theming, HTML5, CSS3 enable any frontend-layout with reasonable effort
- Scrum & test-driven development

#### Management

- project management supported by <u>Atlassian</u>
- training and supervision of international Plone themers, content editors and designers
- analyze software requirements, design software strategies
- software release management
- sometimes it is just good to teach some kids

**Senior Developer** – Planquadrat Software - Integration GmbH cakephp, model-view-controller, software-design, ajax, rest, api, backend

 $2007 \rightarrow 2009$ 

I was responsible to implement the lead-design of a flexible booking-engine, which allows subscribed customers to manage any kind of rentals and set up a very customizable pricing system in a web-based backend. It is implemented in cake-php, followed the best-practises, provides a RESTful API, different embedding solutions for 3rd party websites/CMS and is in use for a wide range from real estate to scooter rentals.

IT-Consultant - independent

 $2005 \rightarrow 2008$ 

ajax, flash, security, typo3, php, frontend, project-management

Many mini-websites (joomla, wordpress,), some flash-games, support a multi-media art show, server-side image processing for a photo-portal, Typo3 frontend for a Ruby-on-Rails video-portal (sightseeker.de) and giving many Typo3 training seminars across Germany. I really like to teach and help others to understand and do by things by themself.

PHP Developer, Consultant & Trainer - iT-NetService GmbH

php, sql, mysql, model-view-controller, svn, backend, project-management

 $2003 \rightarrow 2005$ 

In this time I moved away from theming and started as php-developer for a new real estate management software. I really understood coding in this time and was mentored on a high professional level. I was also introduced to MySQL, SVN and the Model-View-Controller structure as well as the basics of web-security as cross-site-scripting, sql-injections and code injections. Besides the coding I was responsible for courses requested by customers (Typo3 beginners or developer) as well as the companies next-generation themers.

**CMS Themer** – iT-NetService GmbH html, css, javascript, typo3, typoscript

 $2002 \rightarrow 2003$ 

I started professional webdevelopment by implementing custom themes for the Typo3 CMS for a wide range of customers, learning and using TypoScript to get all the tweaks and useful features integrated. I we used project management software to log billable times and svn as version control. With 1-2 websites per month I learned how to communicate with customers and coordinate all tasks to finalize projects in time.

Education

Computer Science – University Leipzig, Germany regex, software-design, testing, java, database, security

 $2004 \rightarrow 2007$ 

**Media & IT ("Medieninformatik")** – HTWK Leipzig, Germany html, css, c, java

2001 → 2004

Public Artifacts

Problems with the facebook share? The wrong text or image shows up? - Rasta.Online -

http://rasta.online/education/software-development/2015/12/11/facebook-share-dialog-and-open-graph-meta-tags.html.

This article explains how to set all needed information in open graph tags of your website and how to use the debugger tools to get the latest results.

Free software tools for your success — Rasta.Online – http://rasta.online/education/software-development/2015/12/08/free-softeware-tools-for-your-online-business-success.html

This is a software guide shows free tools to organize a digital startup company. It discusses SEO, marketing, team management, crowdfunding and known best pr...

faster, cheaper, safer — Rasta.Online – http://rasta.online/education/software-development/2015/11/19/faster-cheaper-safer html

Exposure and Performance is most important? You might not need to pay hosting anymore when using a pre-compiled website and perform best in SEO and pageload ...

CMS ... Wordpress, Joomla!, Drupal, Django, Typo3 or Plone — Rasta.Online – http://rasta.online/education/software-development/2015/11/17/cms-wordpress-joomla-drupal-django-typo3-plone.html

What is a website? For what do we need CMS? This article explains the basics of internet and shows commonly used solutions as Wordpress, Joomla!, Drupal, Dja...

**Apps & Software** 

 $\textbf{Rapid Agile Software Website} - \texttt{http://RapidAgileSoftware.github.io} \ javascript, \ \texttt{html}, \ css, \ sass, \ jekyll$ 

Apr 2020

created personal online profile

**Others** 

Background - Background

I was born in 1981 in Germany and I got my fair share of education and professional experience there. In 2009 I traveled the world to figure out that I like to life in countries without winter and better fit into a company which respects and encourage independent and self-organised work. I'm fluent in written and spoken German and English and well used to support customers and collegues from many countries.

Readings

**Promote Your Content with Structured Data Markup** – Google Developers – https://developers.google.com/structured-data/

Using Structured Data for SEO purpose

**Tools** 

First Computer: Favorite Editor:

Intel 100 PyCharm